Guide to the Ramiro Cortés music recordings 1950s-1996
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- 109-174: Reel-to-reel audiotapes, audiocassettes and CDs (Box 4)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Antony and Cleopatra incidental music, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 12)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Antony and Cleopatra party music, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 130)
  - Stravinsky/Cortés Concertino, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 131)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Concerto for Harpsichord and Strings, circa 1972; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 132)
    Composed in 1971-1972
    Performed by the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Malcolm Hamilton, solo
    Conducted by Neville Marriner
  - Ramiro Cortés: Movements in Variation, 1972 November 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 133)
    Performed at the University of Utah in Salt Lake City, Utah
    Utah Symphony Orchestra conducted by Ramiro Cortés
  - Unknown composition, 1973 November 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 134)
    Performed by the Strings of University of Utah Symphony with Reve Parisien and Naomi Farr
  - Ramiro Cortés: Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet, Ode to a Nightingale Tenor, Piano Partita for Solo Violin, circa 1970-1971; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 135)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet, Ode to a Nightingale Tenor, Piano Partita for Solo Violin, circa 1970-1971; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 136)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Second String Quartet, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 137)
  - Incidental music to Goldsmith's She Stoops to Conquer, 1971 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 138)
    Recorded by Stephen Markham at the Hancock Auditorium, Hollywood for University of Southern California Drama Department
    University of Southern California Chamber Orchestra conducted by Ramiro Cortés
  - Chamber ensemble concert, 1983 May 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 139)
    Handel: Concerto no. 11
    Ramiro Cortés: Music for Strings premier
    Arthur Foote: A Night Piece
    Haydn: Symphony no. 7
  - Ramiro Cortés: Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 140)
    Composed in 1975
  - Ramiro Cortés: Little Suite, 1982 January 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 141)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Ode to a Nightingale, 1971 July 24; 1971 February 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 142)
    Performed by Michael Sells, tenor at the University of Southern California
    Performed by Michael Sells, tenor at the University of Utah
    Conducted by JoAnn Ottley
  - Eternal Return, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 143a)
    University of Utah performance
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 143b)
    Germany performance
  - Ramiro Cortés: Movements in Variation, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 144)
    Conducted by Ramiro Cortés
  - Ramiro Cortés: Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 145)
    Performed by the Utah Symphony with Sally Peterson, soloist
    Conducted by the Ramiro Cortés
  - Ramiro Cortés: Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 146)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Ode to a Nightingale, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 147)
    Performed by Michael Sells, tenor and Ramiro Cortés, piano
  - Phi Mu Epsilon composer recital, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 148)
    First half, Nelson
  - Brief Candles, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 149)
    Piano
  - Ramiro Cortés concert, 1982 January 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 150)
  - Contrasts Symphonic Wind Ensemble, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 151)
  - Beethoven: Bagatelle, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 152)
  - Antony and Cleopatra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 153)
  - Reading and Winds, 1982 February 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 154)
  - Ode to Nightingale, Sonata for Violin and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 155)
    Ode to Nightingale performed by JoAnn Ottley, Reve Parisien and Naomi Farr
    Sonata for Violin and Piano performed by Oscar Chausow and Lowell Farr
  - Ramiro Cortés tape 1: chamber and vocal compositions, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 156)
    Trio in One Movement for Violin, Cello and Piano
    Composed in 1959
    Performed by Ross-Kelley and Ramiro Cortés, piano
    Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet
    Composed in 1971
    Ode to a Nightingale
    Composed 1970-1971
    Two Songs on Poems by Ben Jonson
    Performed by the University of Southern Califormia concert choir
    Conducted by James Vail
  - Ramiro Cortés tape 2: orchestral works and concerto, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 157)
    The Eternal Return for Orchestra
    Composed 1963-1966
    Performed by the University of Southern California Symphony
    Conducted by Ingolf Dahl
    Concerto for Violin and String Orchestra
    Composed 1964-1965
    Performed by Eudace Shapiro, violin
    Meditation for String Orchestra
    Composed in 1961
    Performed by the United States International Orchestra
    Conducted by Phillip Lambro
    Selected incidental music from Goldsmith's She Stoops to Conquer
    Performed by the Oliver Goldsmith Chamber Orchestra
    Variations for Orchestra
    Conducted by Walter Ducloux
  - Virginia Richmond vs Schlitz Company, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 159)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Meditation on Christ Lag in Todesbanden,Introduction and Allegro, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 160)
    Performed by the Julliard Orchestra
  - Variations on a Theme by Halsey Stevens on the occasion of his 60th birthday party, 1968 December 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 161)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Night Music for 16, Elegy for Flute and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 162)
  - Shostakovich: Symphony no. 13 conclusion, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 163)
  - Ramiro Cortés: The Eternal Return, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 164)
    Recorded in New York concert
  - Birthday Variations for Ulysses Kay, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 165)
    Theme: Kay's Suite for Strings, 2nd movement
    Variations, 1, 6
    Performed by Ingolf Dahl and Ramiro Cortés, pianist
  - Meditation on Christ Lag in Todesbanden, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 166)
    Congress of Strings
  - Ramiro Cortés: Sinfonia Sacra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 167)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Trio in One Movement, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 168)
  - Silvermine String Quartet, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 169)
  - A Nocturnal upon St. Lucies Day, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 170)
  - Deer Valley Festival, 1988; Audiocassette (Cassette 171)
    Ramiro Cortés: Trio
    Performed by R. Harlow, T. King and J. Jensen
    Brahms: Opus 115
    Performed by R. Harlow, M. Ramos, P. Rosenthal, L. Blackburn and S. Balderston
  - Ramiro Cortés: Second String Quartet, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 172)
    Composed for the Muir Quartet
  - Ramiro Cortés: Orchestration 1 first lecture, Mozart: Symphony Concertanta, 1984 February 26; Audiocassette (Cassette 173)
    Ramiro Cortés conducting student orchestra
    Scowcroft, Slalkind, and Cortés
  - Park City International Music Festival, 1996; Compact disc (Disc 174)
    Recorded Live at the Park City Community Church and the Clockroom at Deer Valley Resort
    Produced by Leslie Harlow and Russell Harlow of the Park City International Music Festival
    There are three extra CD copies of this same program in the Archives